<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<examples>
    <!-- ORIGINAL EXAMPLES -->
    <example>
        <user:input>Bears are at the door, did you leave the garbage out?</user:input>
        <score>4</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>BAD: in the vocabulary table it did not show the Japanese characters, the cells are just blank</reason>
            <reason>BAD: the beginner sentence is unnecessary, should just start showing the vocabulary table</reason>
            <reason>BAD: In the clues we should not provide the polite form of verbs, because the student needs to figure that out</reason>
            <reason>BAD: The sentence structure says too much. We really want something conceptual like this: [Location] [Subject] [Verb], [Object] [Verb-past]?</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            Let's break down the sentence into smaller parts. Here's a possible table of vocabulary to get you started:

            | Japanese | Romaji | English
            |          | kuma   | bear
            |          | tobira | door
            |          | gomi   | garbage
            |          | noko   | leave behind |

            Now, let's think about the sentence structure. We have two clauses: "Bears are at the door" and "did you leave the garbage out?".
            For the first clause, we can use the verb (aru) which means "to exist" or "to be present". We'll need to figure out the correct form of the verb to use.
            For the second clause, we can use the verb (nokosu) which is a more polite way of saying "to leave behind". Again, we'll need to figure out the correct form of the verb to use.

            Here's a possible sentence structure:

            [Clause 1: Bears are at the door]
            [Subject] wa [Location] ni [Verb] desu
            [Clause 2: did you leave the garbage out?]
            [Verb] masu ka

            Your turn! Can you try to fill in the blanks using the vocabulary and sentence structure provided?
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

    <example>
        <user:input>Bears are at the door, did you leave the garbage out?</user:input>
        <score>10</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>GOOD: Doesn't provide verbose text at the start, and shows vocabulary immediately</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Shows conceptual sentence structure</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Clues don't give away any of the tense or conjugations</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            Cheatsheet:
            | Word             | Japanese    | Type                          |
            |-----------------|-------------|-------------------------------|
            | bear            | 熊（くま）     | Noun                          |
            | door            | ドア          | Noun                          |
            | garbage         | ゴミ          | Noun                          |
            | to be (location)| いる          | Intransitive Ichidan Verb     |
            | to leave        | 出す（だす）    | Transitive Godan Verb         |

            Sentence structure:
            [Location] [Subject] [Verb], [Object] [Verb-past]?

            Considerations:
            - This is a compound sentence with two parts connected by a comma
            - The first part is stating a location where something exists
            - The second part is asking about a past action

            Possible next steps:
            - attempt an answer
            - ask clues about location marking
            - ask clues about how to connect two sentences
            - ask clues about question formation
            - ask clues about verb conjugation
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

    <!-- NEW EXAMPLES -->
    <example>
        <user:input>The cat is sleeping in the garden. Did you feed it already?</user:input>
        <score>3</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>BAD: The vocabulary table repeats "cat" multiple times</reason>
            <reason>BAD: Provided the full conjugation for "to sleep" instead of letting the student figure it out</reason>
            <reason>BAD: Overly detailed sentence structure including particles and tense endings</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            First, let's talk about the sentence. We have:
            "The cat is sleeping in the garden." and "Did you feed it already?"

            Vocabulary:
            | Japanese | Romaji | English |
            | 猫       | neko   | cat
            | 庭       | niwa   | garden
            |         | neteimasu | sleeping
            |         | tabemashita | ate/has eaten
            |         | ...      | ...

            Sentence Structure:
            - "The cat is sleeping in the garden" → [Subject] は [Location] で [Verb + ている form]
            - "Did you feed it already?" → [Subject] は [Object] を [Verb] ました か

            In Japanese, you can use te-iru form to express ongoing action, so "sleeping" becomes "寝ています（neteimasu）". 
            For "Did you feed it already?" you can say "あげましたか？" but that would be the polite form.

            Try to put this all together in a full sentence. Remember to watch out for particles!
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

    <example>
        <user:input>The cat is sleeping in the garden. Did you feed it already?</user:input>
        <score>9</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>GOOD: Starts with concise vocabulary</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Uses a conceptual sentence structure without conjugations</reason>
            <reason>MINOR: Could clarify that "to feed" often uses a different verb than "to give"</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            Vocabulary Table:
            | Word        | Japanese   | Type    |
            |------------|------------|---------|
            | cat        | 猫（ねこ）    | Noun    |
            | garden     | 庭（にわ）     | Noun    |
            | to sleep   | 寝る（ねる）    | Verb    |
            | to feed    | あげる       | Verb    |

            Sentence Structure Concept:
            1. [Subject] [Location] [Verb -ing].
            2. [Subject] [Object] [Verb-past]?

            Considerations:
            - For "sleeping," you’ll need the continuous form of "寝る（ねる）".
            - "Did you feed it already?" needs a past tense or perfect tense nuance in Japanese.
            - Don’t forget to consider particles like に, で, or を.
            - In natural Japanese, you might omit the subject if it’s clear from context.

            Tips:
            - Double-check if you want a polite form or a plain form.
            - Think about which particle to use to indicate location or direct object.
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

    <example>
        <user:input>Tomorrow, I want to watch a movie. Do you want to come along?</user:input>
        <score>10</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>GOOD: Immediately presents minimal vocabulary</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Clearly states conceptual structure without giving away conjugations</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Encourages the student to figure out the correct grammar forms</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            Vocabulary:
            | Word        | Japanese       | Type    |
            |------------|----------------|---------|
            | tomorrow   | 明日（あした）    | Adverb/Time |
            | movie      | 映画（えいが）     | Noun    |
            | to watch   | 見る（みる）       | Verb    |
            | to come    | 来る（くる）       | Verb    |
            | want       | ～たい           | Auxiliary (desire) |

            Sentence Structure:
            [Time] [Subject] [Object] [Verb-desire]. [Subject] [Verb]?

            Considerations:
            - For "I want to watch," you can use the ～たい form of 見る（みる）.
            - Asking someone to come along can be a question that uses a plain or polite form of 来る（くる）.
            - Particles are not provided—figure out where を or に might be needed.
            - Think about whether you need to specify the subject in Japanese or if context is enough.

            Hints:
            - Remember to consider casual vs. polite levels.
            - If the context is friendly, you might omit subjects and simply say something like 「明日映画見たい。いっしょに来る？」 in casual speech (but you still need to handle correct conjugations yourself).
        </assistant:output>
    </example>
</examples>
