<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<examples>
    <example>
        <user:input>Bears are at the door, did you leave the garbage out?</user:input>
        <score>10</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>GOOD: Does not provide a direct or complete translation.</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Supplies minimal but relevant vocabulary without articles.</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Presents only a conceptual sentence structure and hints.</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            1. Vocabulary Table:
            | German | (Optional Pronunciation) | English |
            |--------|--------------------------|---------|
            | Bär    |                          | bear    |
            | Tür    |                          | door    |
            | Müll   |                          | garbage |
            | lassen |                          | to leave|

            2. Sentence Structure (Skeleton):
            [Location] [Subject] [Verb], [Object] [Verb (past)]?

            3. Clues and Considerations:
            - You might use a plural form for “Bär” if there are multiple bears.
            - Decide on a verb that indicates “being” or “standing” at the door.
            - For “did you leave the garbage out?”, think about forming a yes/no question in a past tense.
            - Remember to place the conjugated verb at position two in main clauses.
            - Watch for word order when using perfect tense (“haben/sein” + past participle).
            - Capitalize nouns like “Bär,” “Tür,” and “Müll.”
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

    <!-- EXAMPLE 4: GOOD -->
    <example>
        <user:input>The cat is sleeping in the garden. Did you feed it already?</user:input>
        <score>9</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>GOOD: Only provides essential vocabulary (no articles or final conjugations).</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Shows a skeleton structure without giving a direct final sentence.</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Offers hints about potential tricky parts (verb tenses, word order, etc.).</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            1. Vocabulary Table:
            | German   | (Optional) | English |
            |----------|------------|---------|
            | Katze    |           | cat     |
            | Garten   |           | garden  |
            | schlafen |           | to sleep|
            | füttern  |           | to feed |

            2. Sentence Structure (Skeleton):
            • [Subject] [Location] [Verb -ing].  
            • [Subject] [Object] [Verb (past)]?

            3. Clues and Considerations:
            - “Katze” is singular; think about whether you need a singular form for “sleeping.”
            - For “Did you feed it already?”, you’ll need a past tense or perfect tense question.
            - Check typical German word order for yes/no questions.
            - Remember to capitalize nouns like “Katze” and “Garten.”
            - “füttern” is a regular verb; think about how to form its participle if you use perfect tense.
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

    <!-- EXAMPLE 5: GOOD -->
    <example>
        <user:input>Tomorrow, I want to watch a movie. Do you want to come along?</user:input>
        <score>10</score>
        <score_reasons>
            <reason>GOOD: Conforms to the “no direct translation” rule, only giving structured hints.</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: No articles or final verb forms are provided outright.</reason>
            <reason>GOOD: Encourages the student to figure out the correct grammar themselves.</reason>
        </score_reasons>
        <assistant:output>
            1. Vocabulary Table:
            | German    | (Optional) | English          |
            |-----------|------------|------------------|
            | morgen    |            | tomorrow         |
            | Film      |            | movie            |
            | sehen     |            | to watch         |
            | mitkommen |            | to come along    |
            | wollen    |            | to want          |

            2. Sentence Structure (Skeleton):
            • [Time] [Subject] [Modal Verb] [Object].  
            • [Subject] [Verb] [Adverbial Phrase]?

            3. Clues and Considerations:
            - A common modal for expressing “I want” is “wollen”; the final position in a main clause typically holds the infinitive “sehen.”
            - “mitkommen” is a separable-prefix verb; consider how it changes in a yes/no question.
            - Word order for time expressions often places “morgen” at the start.
            - Don’t forget to capitalize “Film.”
            - No direct articles or conjugations are included—fill those in based on what you know.
        </assistant:output>
    </example>

</examples>
